Guide to the Maria Mitchell Papers, 1843-2016 (bulk 1853-1889)
Vassar College Libraries Archives and Special Collections
- SERIES X. GLASS PLATE NEGATIVES, 1871-1890
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 May 1 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 17)
    Notes: "Spot of April 27 photographed."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 May 3 11:05 AM (Neg. Box 17)
    Notes: "Spots of April 27 photographed, and another large spot with faculae which has just come on the Sun."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 May 4 11:05 AM (Neg. Box 17)
    Notes: "Spot of April 24 is still on Sun, but is not seen in photograph. The spot of May 3 has a companion spot just by it. This large spot when observed with the equatorial showed numerous small spots. The edge of the umbra was jagged, that of the penumbra was wavy."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Braislin, 1880 May 5 12:01 PM (Neg. Box 17)
    Notes: "Large spot of May 3 photographed."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 May 6 11:05 AM (Neg. Box 17)
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Braislin, 1880 May 10 11:45 AM (Neg. Box 26)
    Notes: "Spot of May 3 photographed"
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 May 12 11:45 AM (Neg. Box 17)
    Notes: "Spot of May 3 is fast disappearing from limb of Sun."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 May 24 11:45 AM (Neg. Box 17)
    Notes: "A spot has just come on the edge of the Sun."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 May 29 12:05 PM (Neg. Box 1)
    Notes: "The spots first seen May have fairly increased and there are now two larger spots and eight or ten smaller ones. No photographs have been taken since May 24 on account of the intense heat, the thermometer – 90° and 92°. On May 28 the smaller spots formed an acute angle to the left of the large spot. The sun spots are the group near the middle. The other spots are defects in the work or on the glass. -M.M."
  - Sunspots, observed by, 1880 Jun 3 12:01 PM (Neg. Box 17)
    Notes: "Spots of May 24 and June 1 photographed. Duplicate."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 Jun 3 11:55 AM (Neg. Box 17)
    Notes: "Spots of May 24 and June 1 photographed. They are small and very faint. The spots of May 24 are near the edge, moving off; those of June 1 are approaching the center."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 Jun 14 11:55 AM (Neg. Box 17)
    Notes: "A small spot has just appeared on the Sun. It is very faint in photograph but may be seen on the edge of Sun away from the second impression."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 Jun 16 11:45 AM (Neg. Box 25)
    Notes: "The group of June 14 has advanced upon the sun and has separated into one large spot followed by several small spots surrounded by faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Wentworth, 1880 Jun 17 11:55 AM (Neg. Box 25)
    Notes: "Group of June 14 photographed. Another spot has just appeared."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Bush, 1880 Jun 18 12:01 PM (Neg. Box 25)
    Notes: "Groups of June 17 photographed."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Bush, 1880 Sep 29 12:35 PM (Neg. Box 17)
    Notes: "Four groups of spots, with smaller ones surrounding them, seen on the sun."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Bush, 1880 Oct 8 12:02 PM; [envelope only] (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "Two groups of very small spots not seen in photograph."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Bush, 1880 Oct 9 12:25 PM; [envelope only] (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "Two groups of very small spots which do not appear in photograph."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Bush, 1880 Oct 11 12:15 PM; [envelope only] (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "Two groups of very small spots were seen by the telescope, but they do not appear in photograph"
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Bush, 1880 Oct 13 12:02 PM (Neg. Box 17)
    Notes: "One group of very small spots not seen in photograph is just disappearing from Sun. Another group of larger spots with faculae has just come on. This group is seen in photograph."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Case, 1880 Oct 19 12:02 PM; [envelope only] (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "Four groups of spots photographed. Three of these groups are accompanied by small spots."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Bush, 1880 Oct 20 12:02 PM (Neg. Box 23)
    Notes: "Two new spots have appeared on the Sun making with the others, which have divided, eight distinct spots. Som of these have faculae and smaller spots surrounding them."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Bush, 1880 Oct 27 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 23)
    Notes: "One group of spots photographed on the sun. No photograph has been taken since Oct. on account of cloudiness."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Case, 1880 Oct 28 12:02 PM; [envelope only] (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "Two small groups of spots are on the Sun. but do not appear in photograph."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Case, 1880 Nov 1 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 17)
    Notes: "A group of four spots photographed on Sunday - Nov. 8-9 No spots (plate destroyed)"
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Case, 1881 25 Jan 12:01 PM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Two groups of spots seen in both impressions. One group has at least four large spots with faculae. Their spots were first seen today."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Harrison, 1881 29 Jan 12:02 PM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Four groups of spots consisting of at least nine distinct spots."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Bush, 1881 Feb 3 12:02 PM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: ""Two groups of spots. One leaving, the other coming on Sun. These spots were first seen Feb. 2. but were not photographed since the thermometer (?) was but 2° at 12 m.""
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Harrison, 1881 Feb 4 12:01 PM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "One group seen Feb. 2 has disappeared leaving one group. This consists of at least four different spots."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Raymond, 1881 Feb 5 [12:12 PM?] (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Group of Feb. 4 photographed This group has divided into several"
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Raymond, 1881 Feb 7 12:20 PM (Neg. Box 36.9)
    Notes: "Four groups of spots, the separate ones quite distinct."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Harrison, 1881 Feb 9 12:01 PM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "Three group(s) of the spots of Feb. 7 photographed."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Harrison, 1881 Feb 11 (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "Two groups of spots. The group just on the limb of the Sun has faculae."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Whitney, 1881 Feb 14 12:01 PM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "Two groups of spots. One going off. The other just appearing on limb of the Sun."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Whitney, 1881 Feb 15 12:01 PM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "Three groups of small spots two just appearing on the limb of the Sun"
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Whitney, 1881 Feb 16 12:02 PM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "Four groups of spots. Two on either limb. In one spot the umbra and penumbra are distinctly seen."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Whitney, 1881 Feb 22 [12:12 PM?] (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Seven groups consisting of at least twelve separate spots. Duplicate."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Whitney, 1881 Feb 22 11:58 AM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Seven groups of spots consisting of at least twelve separate spots."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Whitney, 1881 Feb 25 12:01 PM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Five groups of spots, Four in the same parallel, and one other quite near the edge. These groups have changed very much since they were first seen Feb. 22.” The folder then contains a slip of paper diagramming the Sun spots of Feb. 24th.-- “Sun spots on Feb. 24. 1881."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Whitney, 1881 Mar 7 12:05 PM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "One very small spot one the sun. The larger – is not a spot."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Whitney, 1881 Mar 8 12:01 PM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "The small spot of March 7 photographed."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Whitney, 1881 Mar 15 12:20 PM (Neg. Box 36.6)
    Notes: "Remarkable spots on Sun. Five groups, the largest of which shows thirteen separate ones in the photograph. Seen through the telescope this group gave other smaller ones and faculae. The groups changed perceptibly during the day."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Whitney, 1881 Mar 16 12:01 PM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Groups of March 15 photographed. The larger cluster has changed but little."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney, 1881 Mar 25 12:07 PM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "One group of Mch. 15 photographed. It is just leaving the Sun's limb. One small spot is seen near the center of Sun. - No photographs have been taken since Mch. 16 on account of the heavy clouds. On only one day since then could the sun be viewed with the telescope."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Whitney, 1881 Apr 4 12:05 PM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Three small groups of spots seen in the photograph. These spots were first seen today."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Whitney, 1881 Apr 29 12:01 PM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Small spot near edge of Sun."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Whitney, 1881 May 4 12:01 PM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Three groups of small spots. In photograph only one spot can be distinguished in two of the groups."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Hodge, 1881 May 9 (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Two of the groups of May 4 are seen near center of Sun. - No photographs taken on May 10, 11, 12, 13 on account of extreme heat, the [thermometer] being between 80° and 90.° No picture taken May 14 because I was printing negatives. There is a quite large spot on seen with small ones about it. The umbra and penumbra are distinctly marked."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Whitney, 1881 May 24 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "Two groups of spots. One group contains six distinct spots which can be seen in photo. The other has several(?)."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Whitney, 1881 May 25 [12:12 PM?] (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Two groups containing small spots. The telescope – one of the large spots into two."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Whitney, 1881 May 26 12:05 PM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Spots of May 25th"
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Whitney, 1881 May 30 12:10 PM (Neg. Box 36.1)
    Notes: "Large group of spots with faculae. There are five large distinct ones."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Hodge, 1881 May 31 12:05 PM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Spots of May 30. which have grown larger and separated more."
  - Observed by [unknown], [1881 Jun 1?] (Neg. Box 22)
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Whitney, 1881 Jun 1 12:01 PM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "Spots of May 30 photographed."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Whitney, 1881 Jun 6 12:01 PM (Neg. Box 4)
    Notes: "Spots of May 30, which have grown(?) smaller and quite indistinct."
  - Sunspots, observed by Hodge and Whitney, 1881 Jun 6 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Spots of May 30th"
  - Sunspots, observed by Arnold and Whitney, 1881 Nov 10 12:30 PM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Four groups. One large one just coming on."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Boyd, 1881 Nov 11 12:03 PM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Same groups and Nov. 10th"
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Boyd, 1881 Nov 16 12:02 PM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Large spot of No. 11 in center and large group coming on."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Boyd, 1881 Nov 17 12:16 PM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Same groups as on the 16th"
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Boyd, 1881 Nov 22 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Large group of 17th past middle. Large spot passing off. Cloud over sun."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Boyd, 1881 Nov 30 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Some large spots as on 28th."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Boyd, 1881 Dec 5 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Spot of Nov. 30th past middle. Large group since appeared. Branches interfered"
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Boyd, 1881 Dec 8 12:35 PM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Large group of Dec. 5 past center. Large spot passing off. Another just coming on."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Boyd, 1881 Dec 10 12:40 PM (Neg. Box 22)
    Notes: "Large group of Dec. 8th passing off – Two new spots have appeared."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Bush, 1882 Jan 5 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 17)
    Notes: "Same groups as on June 4th"
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Jan 12 12:18 PM (Neg. Box 26)
    Notes: "Two groups, one of them just coming on. Also a Third, faint in negative; all preceding middle"
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Jan 14 12:22 PM (Neg. Box 26)
    Notes: "Same group as on 12th"
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Jan 23 12:20 PM (Neg. Box 6)
    Notes: "Two spots—preceding middle."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Feb 2 12:20 PM (Neg. Box 6)
    Notes: "One large spot in group past middle and two faint ones."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Feb 3 12:22 PM (Neg. Box 6)
    Notes: "Same spots as seen on 2nd with one new group preceding middle."
  - Observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Feb 8 12:35 PM (Neg. Box 6)
    Notes: "Poor"
  - Observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Feb 11 12:40 PM (Neg. Box 26)
  - Observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Feb 14 12:20 PM (Neg. Box 19)
  - Observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Feb 15 12:21 PM (Neg. Box 6)
  - Observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Feb 17 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 6)
  - Observed by Whitney and Boyd, 1882 Feb 18 12:40 PM (Neg. Box 26)
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Feb 27 12:21 PM (Neg. Box 26)
    Notes: "Small group near middle (Another was seen in negative). Spot coming on."
  - Observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Feb 28 12:20 PM (Neg. Box 17)
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Boyd, 1882 Mar 2 12:12 PM (Neg. Box 23)
    Notes: "Small group of Feb. 28 has disappeared."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Mar 3 12:15 PM; [envelope only] (Neg. Box 17)
    Notes: "Two small spots which were not seen yesterday."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Mar 8 12:18 PM (Neg. Box 20)
    Notes: "Group on preceding limb. Large spot on following limb. Duplicate."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Mar 8 12:32 PM (Neg. Box 26)
    Notes: "Group of Mar. 3rd on preceding limb. Two small spots have appeared following it—large spot on following limb."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Mar 11 12:18 PM (Neg. Box 20)
  - Observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Mar 11 12:30 PM (Neg. Box 26)
  - Observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Mar 14 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 26)
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Crane, 1882 Mar 17 12:00 PM (Neg. Box 26)
    Notes: "Large spot on following limb- Group near center. Spots indistinct in negative; exposure too long."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Mar 20 12:27 PM (Neg. Box 26)
    Notes: "The two spots nearest center have appeared since March 17th"
  - Observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Mar 23 12:25 PM (Neg. Box 6)
  - Observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Mar 25 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 6)
  - Observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Mar 28 12:20 PM (Neg. Box 17)
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Witkowsky, 1882 Apr 10 12:10 PM (Neg. Box 26)
    Notes: "(Aperture a)"
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Apr 17 12:12 PM (Neg. Box 36.25)
    Notes: "Large group, accompanied with aurora."
  - Observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Apr 18 12:10 PM (Neg. Box 23)
  - Observed by Whitney and Stanton, 1882 Apr 23 12:10 PM (Neg. Box 26)
    Notes: "Cloudy"
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 Apr 25 12:20 PM (Neg. Box 6)
    Notes: "Large group of 18h on edge"
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 May 3 12:10 PM (Neg. Box 17)
    Notes: "Very large spot coming on. Faint-group further on, not seen in negative-"
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Morris, 1882 May 8 12:35 PM (Neg. Box 26)
    Notes: "Light clouds over sun."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Sudduth, 1882 May 16 12:35 PM (Neg. Box 32)
    Notes: "Large group probably that of April 17th"
  - Observed by [unknown], 1882 May 19 (Neg. Box 26)
    Notes: "[no cover, engraved with date]"
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Sudduth, 1882 May 23 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 6)
    Notes: "One group just on edge. Another following."
  - Observed by Whitney and Sudduth, 1882 May 24 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 6)
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Sudduth, 1882 May 26 12:14 PM (Neg. Box 26)
    Notes: "Spot coming on."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Sudduth, 1882 May 27 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 6)
    Notes: "Very small spot – large --"
  - Observed by Whitney and Sudduth, 1882 May 29 12:18 PM (Neg. Box 17)
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Sudduth, 1882 May 30 12:11 PM (Neg. Box 26)
    Notes: "Faint, small spot, making equilateral triangle with large ones."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Sudduth, 1882 May 31 12:14 PM (Neg. Box 26)
    Notes: "Clouds over sun."
  - Observed by Whtiney and Sudduth, 1882 Jun 2 12:12 PM (Neg. Box 19)
  - Observed by Whitney and Adams, 1882 Jun 5 11:56 AM (Neg. Box 20)
  - Observed by Whitney and Sudduth, 1882 Jun 6 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 23)
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Gardner, 1882 Sep 30 12:00 PM (Neg. Box 6)
    Notes: "Large spots passed middle"
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Gardner, 1882 Oct 1 12:10 PM (Neg. Box 25)
    Notes: "Large nucleus"
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Gardner, 1882 Oct 2 12:12 PM (Neg. Box 13)
    Notes: "Large single nucleus – (with return(?))"
  - Observed by Whitney and Gardner, 1882 Oct 3 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 23)
  - Observed by Whitney and Gardner, 1882 Oct 4 12:06 PM (Neg. Box 23)
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Spafford, 1882 Oct 7 12:00 PM (Neg. Box 19)
    Notes: "Only one small spot."
  - Observed by Whitney and Spafford, 1882 Oct 10 12:07 PM (Neg. Box 19)
  - Observed by Whitney and Gardner, 1882 Oct 14 12:10 PM (Neg. Box 23)
  - Observed by Whitney and Spafford, 1882 Oct 18 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 23)
  - Observed by Whitney and Spafford, 1882 Oct 20 12:03 PM (Neg. Box 23)
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Spafford, 1882 Oct 25 12:02 PM (Neg. Box 25)
    Notes: "Probably the return of large spot of Oct. 2nd"
  - Observed by Whitney and Spafford, 1882 Oct 26 11:59 AM (Neg. Box 23)
    Notes: "4 Cab. Vassar College Observatory"
  - Observed by Whitney and Gardner, 1882 Oct 28 12:00 PM (Neg. Box 20)
    Notes: "Duplicate. Poor"
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Gardner, 1882 Oct 28 12:00 PM (Neg. Box 36.2)
    Notes: "If this can be well printed, make this one of the four; if not, take the Venus transit no. 4"
  - Observed by Whitney and Spafford, 1882 Oct 30 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 23)
  - Observed by Whtiney and Spafford, 1882 Nov 1 12:02 PM (Neg. Box 19)
  - Observed by Whitney and Spafford, 1882 Nov 6 12:04 PM (Neg. Box 23)
  - Observed by Whitney and Spafford, 1882 Nov 7 12:10 PM (Neg. Box 23)
  - Observed by Whitney and Spafford, 1882 Nov 8 12:05 PM (Neg. Box 23)
    Notes: "Poor focus"
  - Observed by Whitney and Spafford, 1882 Nov 9 12:07 PM (Neg. Box 23)
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Spafford, 1882 Nov 15 12:06 PM (Neg. Box 19)
    Notes: "Large group. (with aurora)"
  - Observed by Whitney and Spafford, 1882 Nov 16 12:05 PM (Neg. Box 6)
  - Observed by Whitney and Spafford, 1882 Nov 18 12:10 PM (Neg. Box 26)
    Notes: "Vassar College Observatory"
  - Observed by Whitney and Spafford, 1882 Nov 20 12:00 PM (Neg. Box 23)
  - Observed by Whitney and Spafford, 1882 Nov 21 12:06 PM (Neg. Box 23)
  - Observed by Whitney and Spafford, 1882 Nov 22 12:07 PM (Neg. Box 25)
  - Observed by Whitney and Stanton, 1882 Nov 24 circa 12:00 PM (Neg. Box 23)
  - Observed by Whitney and Spafford, 1882 Nov 27 12:10 PM (Neg. Box 26)
  - Transit of Venus, observed by [unknown], 1882 Dec 6 circa 11:07 AM (Neg. Box 36.23)
    Notes: "No. 1. Transit of Venus. Cloudy. North point 9° 7' East of vertex"
  - Transit of Venus, observed by [unknown], 1882 Dec 6 11:22 AM (Neg. Box 36.1)
    Notes: "No. 2. Transit of Venus. Cloudy"
  - Transit of Venus, observed by [unknown], 1882 Dec 6 11:35:49 AM (Neg. Box 2)
    Notes: "No. 3. Transit of Venus. Cloudy"
  - Transit of Venus, observed by [unknown], 1882 Dec 6 11:49:37 AM; [plate in poor condition] (Neg. Box 36.24)
    Notes: "Transit of Venus. Slightly Cloudy. North point- 21' East of vertex."
  - Transit of Venus, observed by [unknown], 1882 Dec 6 [1:42 PM?] (Neg. Box 36.5)
    Notes: "No. 8. Transit of Venus. Branches of a tree interposed."
  - Observed by Whitney and Gardner, 1882 Dec 16 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 17)
  - Observed by Whitney and Spafford, 1882 Dec 18 12:07 PM (Neg. Box 19)
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Gardner, 1883 Jan 30 12:05 PM (Neg. Box 14)
    Notes: "Small spots. Poor negative"
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Gardner, 1883 Feb 1 12:10 PM (Neg. Box 13)
    Notes: "Four small spots or groups. Poor negative."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Jenckes, 1883 Feb 10 12:10 PM (Neg. Box 32)
    Notes: "Cloudy. Poor negative."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Jenckes, 1883 Mar 2 12:12 PM (Neg. Box 32)
    Notes: "One small spot."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Jenckes, 1883 Mar 13 12:06 PM (Neg. Box 32)
    Notes: "5 groups, 25 spots (all counted) MacDonald, -- 33."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Gardner, 1883 Mar 14 12:31 PM (Neg. Box 32)
    Notes: "4 Groups – 11 spots. (Macdonald)"
  - Observed by Whitney and Gardner, 1883 Mar 18 9:50 AM (Neg. Box 13)
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Jenckes, 1883 Mar 19 12:12 PM (Neg. Box 20)
    Notes: "4 good. 9 spots. Duplicate."
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Jenckes, 1883 Mar 19 12:00 PM (Neg. Box 23)
    Notes: "4 gr. 9 spots."
  - Observed by Whitney and Jenckes, 1883 Apr 4 12:12 PM (Neg. Box 6)
  - Observed by Whitney and Jenckes, 1883 Apr 4 12:04 PM (Neg. Box 20)
  - Observed by Whitney and Gardner, 1883 Apr 6 [1:50 PM?] (Neg. Box 6)
  - Observed by Whitney and Jenckes, 1883 Apr 9 12:03 PM (Neg. Box 6)
  - Observed by Whitney and Jenckes, 1883 Apr 10 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 6)
  - Observed by Whitney and Jenckes, 1883 Apr 18 12:36 PM (Neg. Box 6)
  - Observed by Whitney and Jenckes, 1883 Apr 19 12:17 PM (Neg. Box 6)
  - Observed by Whitney and Gardner, 1883 Apr 21 [12:25 PM?] (Neg. Box 6)
  - Observed by Whitney and Jenckes, 1883 Apr 24 12:02 PM (Neg. Box 6)
  - Observed by Whitney and Jenckes, 1883 Apr 25 12:08 PM (Neg. Box 6)
  - Observed by Whitney and Jenckes, 1883 Apr 30 12:04 PM (Neg. Box 32)
  - Observed by Whitney and Jenckes, 1883 May 1 12:07 PM (Neg. Box 32)
  - Observed by Whitney and Adams, 1883 May 2 12:28 PM (Neg. Box 32)
  - Observed by Whitney and Adams, 1883 May 9 12:00 PM (Neg. Box 32)
  - Observed by Whitney and Adams, 1883 May 12 12:10 PM (Neg. Box 32)
  - Observed by Whitney and Adams, 1883 May 16 12:04 PM (Neg. Box 32)
  - Observed by Whitney and Adams, 1883 May 17 12:06 PM (Neg. Box 32)
  - Observed by Whitney and Gardner, 1883 May 18 12:15 PM (Neg. Box 32)
  - Observed by Whitney and Gardner, 1883 May 19 12:30 PM (Neg. Box 30)
  - Sunspots, observed by Whitney and Adams, 1883 Jun 5 12:18 PM (Neg. Box 15)
    Notes: "Very small spots on the sun. negative by Miss Whitney of Vassar College"
  - Observed by Whitney and Adams, 1883 Jun 7 12:00 PM (Neg. Box 15)
  - Observed by Whitney and Gardner, 1883 Jun 12 12:20 PM (Neg. Box 15)
  - Observed by Whitney and Mitchell, 1883 Oct 3 [1:30 PM?] (Neg. Box 12)
    Notes: "Duplicate. Something wrong. Pulops over exposure"
  - Observed by Whitney and Richmond, 1883 Oct 3 12:07 PM (Neg. Box 15)
  - Observed by Whitney and Richmond, 1883 Oct 5 12:12 PM (Neg. Box 15)
  - Observed by Whitney and Richmond, 1883 Oct 8 12:05 PM (Neg. Box 15)
  - Observed by Whitney and Richmond, 1883 Oct 9 [12:20 PM?] (Neg. Box 15)